const e="accounting",a=200,o=45,t=[{id:128,question:"Balance as per cash book 2, 970  Bank Charges 220 ;Unpresented cheques 3, 950; Uncredited cheques 4,178 ; Direct debit by bank 1, 000 . Determine  the balance as per bank Statement",option:{a:"N1,978",b:"N1,962",c:"N1,522",d:"N2,522"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:129,question:"The records of Superstores shows a loan of  N14,000 from Bala, creditor N8, 000 and assets N190, 500. What is the firm’s capital?",option:{a:"184, 000",b:"1 96, 500",c:"212 000",d:"168, 500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:130,question:"The major advantage of the journal proper is that it",option:{a:"helps in the preparation of the balance sheet",b:"prevents fraud and theft of item of the business",c:"serves as a book of instruction to the bookkeeper",d:"helps the banking industry to be efficient."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:131,question:"One of the objectives of accounting is that it can be used for",option:{a:"business decision making",b:"due process in business",c:"motivating employees",d:"determining the work force."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:132,question:"The ratio that gives the indication of the efficiency of a firm’s sales with respect to cost of goods sold is a",option:{a:"return on capital employed",b:"gross profit margin",c:"net profit margin",d:"return on equity."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:133,question:"The instrument used in analysis and interpretation of financial statement is the",option:{a:"accounting ratios",b:"income and expenditure extract",c:"balance sheet extract",d:"fund accounting."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:134,question:"An item in the balance sheet of a limited liability company is",option:{a:"accrued expenses",b:"lighting and heating",c:"salaries and wages",d:"general expenses."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:135,question:"The documents that provide instant information to firms on their transactions with banks are",option:{a:"bank statement and debit note",b:"cheque stub and deposit slip",c:"cheque book and cashbook",d:"payslip and credit invoice."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:136,question:"Which of the following is the capital reserve of a company?",option:{a:"Accumulated depreciation.",b:"Retained profit.",c:"Share premium",d:"Loss on forfeited shares"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:137,question:"The effect of overstating-revenue expenditure in the profit and loss account is that the",option:{a:"opening stock will be increased",b:"net profit will be understated",c:"net profit will be overstated",d:"opening stock will be decreased"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:138,question:"Which of the following conditions would attract credit and debit notes to be used?",option:{a:"When goods are received from supplier.",b:"When a trial balance is extracted",c:"When a buyer is under or over charged.",d:"When goods are sold to a buyer."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:139,question:"Given:  Drawings [3,500]; Net loss [2, 500]; Capital 1.1.2007 [35, 000], Additional capital [10, 000]. The adjusted capital as at 31 : 12 : 2007 is",option:{a:"N45, 000",b:"N39,000",c:"N35, 000",d:"N46, 000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:140,question:"A receipt is an evidence of",option:{a:"payments",b:"stocking",c:"delivery",d:"discounts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:141,question:"An organization which has records of only personal accounts is said to be operating on the basis of",option:{a:"single entry",b:"real accounts",c:"double entry",d:"nominal accounts"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:142,question:"A proprietor started business with N13, 000.  Assets and liabilities at the end of the year; fixed assets N8, 800, stock N2, 600, debtors  N1 , 000, cash N3, 000 and creditors N1 , 000. Determine the profit for the year?",option:{a:"N2, 400",b:"N3, 000",c:"N9, 800",d:"N 1 , 400"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:143,question:"Badge Plc issued 450, 000 ordinary shares, of 50K each at N1 .50 per share. Application and allotment 45k, 1st call 50k, 2nd call 55k. Determine the amount received on final call.",option:{a:"N225, 000",b:"N236, 250",c:"N 247, 500",d:"N 202, 500"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:144,question:"When goods are sent to the branch at cost plus mark­up, it means that the branch should sell at",option:{a:"a price above or below the stipulated price",b:"any price but not below the transfer price",c:"cost price",d:"a price that is equal to the mark-up."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:145,question:"The income and expenditure account differs from receipts and payments account because it",option:{a:"accounts for notional charges",b:"records transactions that relate to the period on cash basis",c:"records transactions that relate to the period  on accrual basis",d:"accounts for balance of cash at bank."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:146,question:"The major sources of revenue for the state and local governments is",option:{a:"value added tax",b:"statutory allocation",c:"taxes and levies",d:"recurrent revenue."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:147,question:"Which of the following -is -correct about the imprest system?",option:{a:"II and IV",b:"I, III and IV",c:"I, II and III",d:"III and IV"},section:"I.   The amount of the imprest is the same from one organization to another. II. At the end of a fixed period, the petty cashier received a fixed sum of money.  III.  At the end of a period, the petty-cashier is reimbursed, with the amount spent in that period. IV. The system is a method by which a measure  of control is kept on petty cash expenses",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:148,question:"When the fixed capital method is used, the partners share of profits and remunerations are credited to the",option:{a:"current account.",b:"profit and Loss account.",c:"profit and loss appropriation account.",d:"capital account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:149,question:"A discount that is allowed to encourage a debtor to pay off his debt within a period is the",option:{a:"trade discount",b:"annual discount",c:"periodic discount",d:"cash discount."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:150,question:"The costs of acquiring fixed assets and bringing them into the firm is a",option:{a:"general expenses",b:"recurrent expenditure",c:"revenue expenditure",d:"capital expenditure."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:151,question:"The impersonal account is subdivided into",option:{a:"realand nominal accounts",b:"nominal and personal accounts",c:"real and current accounts",d:"personal and real accounts."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:152,question:"Opening balance of Diksacompany was 12, 202, closing balance N15,300, total cash received during the period N40, 000. What was the amount of cash paid during the same period?",option:{a:"N36. 902",b:"N27,502",c:"N12,498",d:"N43.098"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:153,question:"The total cash and cheques received from customers in a control account is derived from the",option:{a:"income and expenditure account",b:"cashbook",c:"purchases day book",d:"sales journal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:154,question:"Which of the followings is a credit item in creditors ledger control account?",option:{a:"Returns outwards.",b:"Discount Received.",c:"Bad debts.",d:"Purchases."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:155,question:"The trader’s capital in a single entry system is ascertained by preparing",option:{a:"gross profit",b:"statement of affairs",c:"suspense account",d:"appropriation account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:156,question:"From the information above, sources of income for a Not-for-profit making organization include",option:{a:"I, III, IV",b:"I, II, III",c:"I, II, IV",d:"I and IV"},section:"I.   Members subscription II.  Fines  from members  III. Donation  IV.  Loan from bank",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:157,question:"Clifford pays rent of  N200 per month for premises. He paid N 2,800 within the year, Compute the prepayment.",option:{a:"N300",b:"N400",c:"N660",d:"N200"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:158,question:"Purchases can be ascertained through the preparation of a",option:{a:"stock account",b:"sales account",c:"total debtors’ control account",d:"total creditors, control account"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:159,question:"When stock is withdrawn, for personal use, the accounting entries is to debit",option:{a:"stock account, credit drawings",b:"drawing account credit stock account",c:"personal account credit cash account",d:"cash account, credit personal account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:160,question:"Sundry debtors in the balance sheet of Onoja Bakery and Sons totaled N800,000. A provision of 2% was made for discount and 5% provision for bad and doubtful debts.  Find the amount for sundry debtors after provision.",option:{a:"N744,800",b:"N 760,000",c:"N784, 000",d:"N744, 000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:161,question:"Which of the following is accounted for in receipts and payments account?",option:{a:"Accrued expenses on annual dances",b:"Subscriptions due but not yet received",c:"Interest on bank deposit",d:"Depreciation of the club house."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:162,question:"When the purchase Consideration is lower than the net asset, the buyer has gained the advantage of",option:{a:"capital reserve",b:"revenue reserve",c:"net-income",d:"net loss"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:163,question:"An increase in government expenditure within a year is taken care of by means of",option:{a:"virement",b:"financial regulations",c:"supplementary estimate",d:"warrant."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:164,question:"A business organization prepares departmental account in order to",option:{a:"ascertain the contribution of each department to the organization",b:"ascertain interdepartmental transfer",c:"build other branches",d:"know the number of departments in the organization."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:165,question:"The objective of departmental account is to",option:{a:"ascertain the amount of profits or losses for the enterprise",b:"ascertain the amount of profits or losses for each department",c:"ascertain the cost of running the organization.",d:"offset the loss of each department."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:166,question:"Which of the following expenses relate to the profit and loss account of a manufacturing firm?",option:{a:"Administrative overhead.",b:"Direct labour",c:"Direct materials.",d:"Work-in-progress."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:167,question:"The difference between book keeping and accounting is that while",option:{a:"book keeping interprets data accounting records it",b:"book keeping is regarded as  the language of the business, accounting ascertains its .strength and weakness",c:"book keeping records data accounting interprets it",d:"book keeping - summaries information, accounting communicates it."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:168,question:"Alaka who owed Saka N15, 000, settled his deb  after- deducting cash discount of 10%. To record the discount in the book of Saka, debit",option:{a:"Saka’s account and credit discount received account",b:"Alaka’s account and credit discount received account",c:"discount received account andcredit Alaka’s account",d:"discount allowed account and credit Alaka’s account."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:169,question:"If the scrap value is now N15, 000, what will be the yearly depreciation using straight line method?",option:{a:"N11 000",b:"N7, 000",c:"N 4, 000",d:"N24. 000"},section:"Use the information below to answer the question that follows. A machine bought for N 35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of N= 9, 000. ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:170,question:"The yearly depreciation using the straight line method would be",option:{a:"N5,200",b:"N6,500",c:"N8, 800",d:"N4, 400"},section:"Use the information below to answer the question that follows. A machine bought for N 35,000 was estimated to have a life span of 5 years with a scrap value of N= 9, 000. ",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:171,question:"The gross profit on manufacture is",option:{a:"N 6,120",b:"N 6,100",c:"N 5,100",d:"N  5,000"},section:"Materials consumed  16,600;	Direct cost 5,400; Factory rent 2,300; Factory  lighting 1,200 	Cost of production to be transferred at cost plus 20% mark-up. ",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:172,question:"The market value of goods produced is",option:{a:"N30,500",b:"N3, 600",c:"N31,600",d:"N31,620"},section:"Materials consumed  16,600;	Direct cost 5,400; Factory rent 2,300; Factory  lighting 1,200 	Cost of production to be transferred at cost plus 20% mark-up. ",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"}],n={subject:e,status:200,total:45,data:t};export{t as data,n as default,a as status,e as subject,o as total};
